Chapter 3 Strategies Section 3.1
Introduction this chapter tries
to lay out the big picture of AI safety
strategy to mitigate the risks explored
previously. As AI
capabilities advance very rapidly, the
strategies designed to ensure
safety must also evolve. The first version
of this
document was written in summer of 2024.
This version
includes the update during the summer of
2020 25.
Through the course of this chapter, we aim
to
provide a structured overview of the
thinking and ongoing
work in AI safety strategy as of 2025. We
acknowledge both established methods and
emerging research directions. We
have categorized mitigations around
preventing misuse of AI safety
mitigations for AGI and asi, and finally
socio technical
approaches that help MIT concerns more
generally across all
categories. Even though we have chosen a
decomposition for
sake of explanation, we advocate for a
comprehensive approach
that combines many of these strategies
instead of pursuing
just a few in isolation. Finally, we have
a
combined strategies section where we
attempt to outline one
potential way that this combination could
look to create
a layered defense in depth framework. At
this point,
the textbook shows Figure 3.1. It depicts
tentative diagrams
summarizing the main high level approaches
to make AI
development safe. The textbook has a
supplementary note titled
beyond the Scope of this chapter, which
we'll skip
over here. At this point There is video
3.1
in the textbook. It covers optional video
from Google
DeepMind AGI safety course. It it gives a
quick
overview of their alignment approach and
how we might
categorize different strategies into
conceptual buckets.